Cory Marshman

Charlotte, NC 28204 | Phone: 980-228-8926 | Email: marshman.cory@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/cory-marshman-6aba24152/ | GitHub: www.github.com/cmarshman | Portfolio: www.corymarshman.com

SUMMARY

Web Developer with a background in operations and project management with 10+ years of business development experience. Verifiable history of contributing directly to company growth and expansion through creative problem solving, attention to detail and the ability to successfully collaborate. Experience includes multi-million dollar project management, budget forecasting, fundraising, program development, team leadership and training, technology solutions, and operations.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Materialize, Bulma, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Express, React, React Native, PHP, Swift, Python, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Algolia, Auth0, Bcrypt, and JWT, passport **Applications:** Visual Studio Code, MySQL Workbench, GitHub, Heroku, Robo 3T and AWS

PROJECTS

React Task Manager - Group Project

Github: https://github.com/cmarshman/shoestring

Deployed URL: https://www.shoestring.me

- Shoestring is a multifunctional web-based application, which allows users to sign up, find friends, upload profile-photos, connect their bank account, utilize a currency converter and, although it is still under development, transfer money between account users.
- Core Responsibilities: Project Lead, JWT login, Main UI/UX design, front end routes,
- **Tools / Languages Used :** MERN Stack, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React.js, Axios, Heroku, Github, Cloudinary API, Plaid API, Exchange Rate API, React-Native

Giftify; **Project Lead - Group Project**

Github: https://github.com/cmarshman/Giftify

Deployed URL: https://giftify-project2.herokuapp.com/

- A multifunctional application which stores user data using Sequelize DB through JawsDB to deploy through
 Heroku. The user is able to login, search gift options through an Etsy API, find video descriptions of
 products embedded in models once selected. They are also able to search an auto populating database
 which allows the user to search 2019 most popular gifts and receive results instantaneously.
- **Core Responsibilities:** Project Lead, developed most of the front end, api and html routes, Algolia DB, Sequelize database set up and inner-join with passport authentication
- Tools / Languages Used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Express.js, Node.js, Passport, Bcrypt Sequelize DB, MySQLWorkbench, MySQL, JawsDB, Algolia DB, Heroku, Github

Intuitive Banana - Group Project

Github: https://github.com/cmarshman/IntuitiveBanana

Deployed URL: https://drbailey13.github.io/IntuitiveBanana/index.html

- A multifunctional music application utilizing a bulma.io framework and multiple 3rd party API's, allowing you to search your favorite artists, follow trending musicians, check the top 5 trending songs on Billboard, read up on the most recent music news, check out local concerts and follow the links to buy tickets.
- **Core Responsibilities:** Project lead, developed front-end, Music News page and NY Times API
- Tools / Languages Used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, NT Times API, Ticketmaster API, Audio-DB API, Github

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Operations Manager

Oct 2019 - Present

SKIPPER, INC.

CHARLOTTE, NC

Oversee all product lines. Set strategy for all product lines, analyze ROI, create more efficient operations and update procedures to reflect industry best practices. Analyze supply and demand trends to ensure needs are met. Advise on resolutions of high-level clients.

- Technologies: React.js, React Native, JavaScript, Node.js, Tableau, Figma, 3rd party API integrations including Strip and MapAnything
- Increased overall efficiency by 45%, by developing and implementing a retraining program for staff.
- Increased overall margins by 10%, through data based modeling and increasing pricing.
- Manage over 70 staff members across multiple product lines and locations, while using a proprietary tech platform to track services provided, delivery times, customer needs and employee support.

DIRECTOR OF OPERATIONS FEB 2018 - OCT 2019

Inner Peaks Charlotte, NC

Head 3 facilities totaling over 65,000 sqft. which serviced 1800+ monthly members and 20000+ monthly day pass users. Directed operations and logistics of 25+ local and regional programs and events per year, with 2000+ participants. Negotiated vendor contracts, track individual program performance and expenses.

- Increased overall memberships by 20%, through developing a corporate membership program.
- Developed and collaborated with the ownership group on a \$4-Million 18,0000 sq. ft. new facility, with a focus on strategic business growth, risk mitigation and facility development.

Program Manager Oct 2015 - Feb 2018

US National Whitewater Center

CHARLOTTE, NC

Oversaw 200+ staff members, who served up to 3500 guests across 1,300 acres, over 12 adventure activity types per day, as a part of a 5-person management team. Pioneered and operated the world's first permanent deep-water solo climbing program as well as the world's first deep water solo-climbing specific aquatics program.

• Increased overall client base by over 800 people a day, by constructing and managing a \$4 million outdoor deep-water climbing facility

ESL Instructor Dec 2008 - Oct 2015

USA, SOUTH KOREA, CHINA, MYANMAR AND OMAN

Taught general, conversational and business English, locally & internationally to students. Organized and hosted English seminars and events for groups of up to 150 students. Engineered curriculum and new study material for courses directed towards students ranging from kindergarten to Professional Adults.

• Traveled to over 35 countries, across 5 continents, completed a 2800-mile unassisted cycling trip across China and a 300-mile unassisted hiking trip through the Sagarmatha region of Nepal.

EDUCATION

Web Development | Coding Certificate; University of North Carolina at Charlotte, Charlotte, NC | 2020 : A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS, 3rd party API integration

Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology: University of North Carolina at Charlotte, Charlotte, NC | 2008: Biological and Evolutionary Anthropology